Max Hawkins

♦ Los Angeles, CA
Image: Los Angeles, CA
Image

Summary

I'm a software engineer with experience developing fast, scalable cloud applications. I recently built Bento, a video transcoding pipeline built on Amazon Web Services. Prior to this, I was an early employee at Facebook, leading strategy and execution execution around release testing, QA, and user sentiment.

Experience

2020 - present

Bento

Co-founder, Software Engineer

- Co-created Bento, an open source, serverless video transcoding pipeline that is deployed to Amazon Web Services
- Implemented a massively parallel approach to transcoding video files using Node.js, AWS Lambda, and Amazon DynamoDB
- Reduced multi-hour transcoding jobs down to minutes by leveraging the scale and concurrency of function-as-a-service architecture
- Resolved timing and concurrency challenges in an event-driven architecture
- Sidestepped AWS Lambda storage limitations by implementing an in-memory, byte streaming approach to video file processing
- Designed and authored a responsive UI dashboard built with React.js, Express, and Bootstrap
- Co-authored Bento case study: https://bento-video.github.io

2018 - 2020

Self-employed

Full Stack Web Developer

 Developed open-source software with technologies such as React, Rails, Express, Node.js, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Docker, HTML, and CSS

2011 - 2014

Facebook

Product Operations, Manager

- Led organizational strategy and execution for QA and user sentiment analysis
- Drove prioritization and resolution of long-standing infrastructure bugs via engineering-wide technical quality initiatives
- Integrated user sentiment analysis into product development and launch cycles

2007 - 2011

Facebook

User Operations

- Embedded with engineering teams to investigate and resolve critical bugs
- Implemented global testing coverage and incident response for daily web releases

Education

2003 - 2007

Stanford University

BA with Honors, Psychology

Skills

Languages and frameworks

Javascript (ES6), React, Redux, Handlebars.js, jQuery, Node.js, Ruby, Express, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud

AWS Lambda, Amazon DynamoDB, Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, AWS CloudFormation, Docker

Web

HTTP, REST, APIs, Git, Event-Driven Architecture, Function as a Service, HTML, CSS